<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Luke Hansford</title>
        <link>http://lukehansford.me</link>
        <description>Experiments and notes from Luke Hansford.</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 12:59:43 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>All rights reserved 2020, Luke Hansford</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Big Muff Eurorack Conversion, Pt. 1]]></title>
            <link>http://lukehansford.me/posts/big-muff-eurorack-conversion-part-1/</link>
            <guid>http://lukehansford.me/posts/big-muff-eurorack-conversion-part-1/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 22:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><em>First up, a caution: this is my first non-guided DIY modular synth project and I'm probably do any number 
of things incorrectly, so take all of this with a grain of salt.</em></p>
<p>Last year I bought a Swollen Pickle pedal to replace my ailing old Russian Big Muff. I probably could have gotten 
the Big Muff repaired, but I was kind of keen to try something new. Not wanting to let it go to waste though, 
and also with the hope of adding a bit more colour to my Eurorack setup, I've decided to have a go at converting 
the Big Muff to something that can be used in a Eurorack system.</p>
<p>This will mean doing the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>Changing the inputs from the 6.35mm inputs used by guitars to the 3.5mm ones used in Eurorack.</li>
<li>Replacing the potentiometers (not really needed for the conversion, but needed to fix my old Big Muff).</li>
<li>Replacing the foot switch with something more comfortable to use by hand.</li>
<li>Converting the pedal to run off a Eurorack power supply.</li>
</ul>
<p>With some possible further additions being:</p>
<ul>
<li>Changing the signal levels to play nicer with synth levels (I'm not certain that this will be necessary).</li>
<li>Adding CV to the tone and sustain knobs (and maybe the volume knob).</li>
<li>Adding dry/wet control.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="replacingthejacks">Replacing the Jacks</h2>
<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/nLKKHHF.jpg" alt="Starting position" /></p>
<p>My first step was to change the 6.35mm jacks for 3.5mm ones. This turned out to be a much easier process 
than I expected. First I removed the enclosure (which required hooking up a new LED as the original LED 
is actually embedded into the pedal case), followed by desoldering the old jacks (which I'll definitely be keeping
as they seem pretty solid).</p>
<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/rW8qIAh.jpg" alt="After desoldering the first jack" /></p>
<p>The jacks on the Big Muff originally came out the back of the case, however as I'm going to need them to be on the front panel I 
soldered them on with a bit of connecting wire (I haven't yet decided where they'll be positioned on the front panel).</p>
<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/QMLoSkQ.jpg" alt="First jack soldered on" /></p>
<p>You'll notice two differences between the jacks I soldered on. First is that I soldered the first one on the wrong side of 
the panel! I'm hoping it won't be too much of a hassle in the future, but if it is then it's pretty easy to fix anyway. The other difference is the extra wire coming off the second jack (the input jack). This connection is important for triggering the LED on 
when a cable is plugged in, so make sure to get that one in if you're following along at home.</p>
<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/pECMryD.jpg" alt="Second jack soldered" /></p>
<p>Amazingly it worked right off the bat! Well kind of - even prior to opening it up my Big Muff can barely have been considered to 
have been "working right". So my next task is to rectify that and return it to its original distorted glory.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.lukehansford.me/articles/big-muff-eurorack-conversion-part-2/">Next step, changing the potentiometers.</a>;</p>]]></description>
            <author>mail@lukehansford.me (Luke Hansford)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Big Muff Eurorack Conversion, Pt. 2]]></title>
            <link>http://lukehansford.me/posts/big-muff-eurorack-conversion-part-2/</link>
            <guid>http://lukehansford.me/posts/big-muff-eurorack-conversion-part-2/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 22:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><em><a href="http://www.lukehansford.me/articles/big-muff-eurorack-conversion-part-1/">Check out part one first!</a></em></p>
<h2 id="newpotentiometers">New Potentiometers</h2>
<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/T4oexNa.jpg" alt="New pots" /></p>
<p>The reason for my Big Muff not being used in the first place was the real old potentiometers making a lot 
of unneeded noise when using it. Unfortunately replacement pots of the same size are really hard to come 
by. Instead I decided to use the standard size pots (you can see the difference in the pic above) and just 
make the panel holes bigger to accommodate them.</p>
<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/tFJoQKY.jpg" alt="First pot replaced" /></p>
<p>Replacing the pots was simple enough - cut the wires, solder on the new ones, done.</p>
<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/KHGZwn4.jpg" alt="https://imgur.com/KHGZwn4" /></p>
<p>The only outlier was that yellow wire - I have no idea what it's supposed to connect too! Regardless, 
it worked out fine. Check out the crunchy results in the clip below.</p>
<div class="iframe-wrapper">
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3Po1nA8cZj4" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>
<p><a href="http://www.lukehansford.me/articles/big-muff-eurorack-conversion-part-3/">Part 3: Changing the switch and connecting to a Eurorack power supply</a>;</p>]]></description>
            <author>mail@lukehansford.me (Luke Hansford)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Big Muff Eurorack Conversion, Pt. 3]]></title>
            <link>http://lukehansford.me/posts/big-muff-eurorack-conversion-part-3/</link>
            <guid>http://lukehansford.me/posts/big-muff-eurorack-conversion-part-3/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2018 11:50:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><em><a href="http://www.lukehansford.me/articles/big-muff-eurorack-conversion-part-1/">Part One</a></em>
<em><a href="http://www.lukehansford.me/articles/big-muff-eurorack-conversion-part-2/">Part Two</a></em></p>
<h2 id="switchingtheswitchconvertingthepowertoeurorackformat">Switching the switch / Converting the power to Eurorack format</h2>
<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/lfKEt4B.jpg" alt="The new switch" /></p>
<p>Foot switches are, understandably, a little hard to press down. They're built to withstand the unsubtle 
kicks of a guitarist in motion, but applying that much pressure to the Big Muff as it sits in my Eurorack case 
make me worry it'll do damage to the case (doubly so as my case is made out of cardboard!).</p>
<p>So the next task in my Big Muff Eurorack conversion was to replace the foot switch with a toggle switch. The 
original switch was a 3PDT switch (a less common variation of switch, but one that allows for proper signal bypass), 
so it was just a matter of tracking down a 3PDT toggle switch (<a href="https://www.aliexpress.com/item/MYLB-AC-250V-2A-125V-5A-ON-ON-2-Position-3PDT-Toggle-Switch/32746132468.html">I used these ones</a>) and switching over the wires.</p>
<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/IynmfWK.jpg" alt="Not quite right" /></p>
<p>As you can see, it technically worked, but I forgot to account for the size of the hole in the panel. My current 
hack solution is to duct tape it in while I think of a more long-term fix.</p>
<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/VnUhfmB.jpg" alt="The step-down circuit prior to soldering" /></p>
<p>My next step was to get the pedal running off my eurorack case's power supply. This involved adding a 
shrouded 10-pin header for connecting to the power bus board, and then adding a circuit to drop the 12v power 
provided by the case's power supply down to the 9v level expected by the Big Muff.</p>
<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/pIpXr2j.jpg" alt="The step-down circuit post soldering and attaching to the PCB" /></p>
<p>The circuit utilises an LM7809 component to drop the voltage down to 9v, and is based on some of the 
talk in <a href="https://www.muffwiggler.com/forum/viewtopic.php?t=115780">this thread over at Muff Wiggler</a>. 
I soldered the components on to some perfboard and attached that to the Big Muff's PCB using a 
standoff. It's a bit wobbly, and the whole board is just hanging from wires attached to the front panel, 
but for now its doing the trick. My next goal is to add CV to the tone and sustain potentiometers (possibly 
volume as well, though I'm not certain yet).</p>]]></description>
            <author>mail@lukehansford.me (Luke Hansford)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DRY Unit Tests in Javascript]]></title>
            <link>http://lukehansford.me/posts/dry-unit-tests-in-javascript/</link>
            <guid>http://lukehansford.me/posts/dry-unit-tests-in-javascript/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>A couple of years ago I started working with a Ruby on Rails codebase and was stunned
by how more well thought out the test were in comparison to Javascript codebases I'd worked with. In
particular I loved that the axiom of DRY (Don't Repeat Yourself) applied to testing - something that
seems obvious to do in hindsight.</p>
<p>Over time I've been picking up the parts of Ruby testing that I found particular useful and applying
them to JS testing. A common pattern I run into is having to test a basic functionality that might
apply across a whole category of component or function types. This post is going to show a small of
example of how we can do this in Javascript.</p>
<p>Let's start with a non-DRY test. The following test suite is for a BlogPost component, and we want
to test that it has HTML metadata (i.e. a title and a description). For this example we're using <a href="https://jestjs.io/">Jest</a> and
<a href="https://testing-library.com/docs/react-testing-library/intro">React Testing Libary</a>, but the concept
should be applicable to whichever testing framework you use.</p>
<pre><code class="javascript language-javascript">  import { render } from '@testing-library/react';

  describe('BlogPost' , () =&gt; {
    render(&lt;BlogPost /&gt;);

    it('Renders metadata', () =&gt; {
      expect(document.title).toEqual(title);
      expect(document.querySelector("meta[name='description']")).toHaveAttribute(
        'content',
        description,
      );
    });
  });
</code></pre>
<p>If our app has other pages, then HTML metadata is probably a useful thing to test for on those as
well. Making our test reusable is as simple as moving it to it's own function that accepts as arguments
the values we want to test for.</p>
<pre><code class="javascript language-javascript">  import { render } from '@testing-library/react';

  function itHasMetadata({ title, description }) {
    it('Renders metatags', () =&gt; {
      expect(document.title).toEqual(title);
      expect(document.querySelector("meta[name='description']")).toHaveAttribute(
        'content',
        description,
      );
    });
  }

  describe('BlogPost' , () =&gt; {
    render(&lt;BlogPost /&gt;);

    itHasMetadata({ title: 'Blog', description: 'Some description' });
  });

  describe('Homepage' , () =&gt; {
    render(&lt;Homepage /&gt;);

    itHasMetadata({ title: 'Home', description: 'Some description' });
  });
</code></pre>
<p>Our metadata test is now DRY! Refactoring our test like this also allows us to compose them.
Let's say our <code>BlogPost</code> and <code>Homepage</code> components share multiple similar tests - we can roll them
into one function that applies thoses tests together.</p>
<pre><code class="javascript language-javascript">  export function itBehavesLikeAPage(title, description, url) {
    itHasMetadata(metadata);
    itHasAHeading();
    itHasACanonicalUrl();
  }

  describe('BlogPost' , () =&gt; {
    render(&lt;BlogPost /&gt;);

    itBehavesLikeAPage({ title: 'Blog', description: '...' });
  });

  describe('HomePage' , () =&gt; {
    render(&lt;Homepage /&gt;);

    itBehavesLikeAPage({ title: 'Home', description: '...' });
  });
</code></pre>
<p>One added benefit of writing our tests in this way is that it makes jumping into Test Driven
Development (TDD) a lot easier. I personally gain a lot from doing TDD, but I often find myself
skipping past the tests because I just want to get my hands dirty coding a solution instead of
spending the time writing a new test. But when writing that test is as simple as importing my
reusable test I don't have any excuse not to do proper TDD!</p>]]></description>
            <author>mail@lukehansford.me (Luke Hansford)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ephemera - 23rd November, 2014]]></title>
            <link>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2014-11-23/</link>
            <guid>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2014-11-23/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2014 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>This the first of (hopefully) many weekly roundups of the content I consume.
While I'm pleased to share this, I'm also starting to become more interested in
storing my activities so I can recall them long into the future. This is one way
of doing that.</p>
<p><span class="more"></span></p>
<h2 id="reading">Reading</h2>
<h3 id="theriseoftheprofessionalcyberathletehttpwwwnewyorkercommagazine20141124goodgame"><a href="http://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2014/11/24/good-game">The Rise of the Professional Cyber Athlete</a></h3>
<p>A nice long article on pro-gaming from the New Yorker. A really nuanced take on
the subject (I think, my gaming skills are less than leet).</p>
<h3 id="aprintmagazineforhackershttpwwwnewyorkercomtechelementsprintmagazinehackers"><a href="http://www.newyorker.com/tech/elements/print-magazine-hackers">A Print Magazine for Hackers</a></h3>
<p>Another techy article from the New Yorker, this time profiling the hacker magazine/bible, 2600.</p>
<h3 id="whatpapersshouldidefinitelyreadasacomputerscienceundergraduatehttpwwwredditcomrlearnprogrammingcomments2jzjh7what_papers_should_i_definitely_read_as_a"><a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/learnprogramming/comments/2jzjh7/what_papers_should_i_definitely_read_as_a/">What papers should I definitely read as a computer science undergraduate?</a></h3>
<p>A reddit question that keeps on giving. As a computer science student this is
an invaluable resource.</p>
<h3 id="mollycrabapples15rulesforcreativesuccessintheinternetagehttpboingboingnet20141104mollycrabapplesrulesforchtml"><a href="http://boingboing.net/2014/11/04/molly-crabapples-rules-for-c.html">Molly Crabapple's 15 rules for creative success in the Internet age</a></h3>
<p>I can't get more descriptive than the article's title. Artist Molly Crabapple gives
some tips that are pretty spot on. I wish I'd had something like this before I started
traversing the music industry.</p>
<h2 id="watching">Watching</h2>
<h3 id="theflash">The Flash</h3>
<p>My brother had been urging me to get into
<a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2193021/">Arrow</a> for a while, and I finally got
the chance to while flying to Singapore last week. Cue intense binge watching
and the search for more. More came in the form of another superhero show based
in the same DC universe - <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt3107288/">The Flash</a>.
The whole concept of the Flash as a superhero felt a little lacking to me at
first, but I've been pleasantly
surprised at how well the creators have done on this show. It switches Arrow's
constant brooding for a bit more humour and some really excellent special
effects, while keeping the better bits such as the flashback stories.</p>
<h2 id="listening">Listening</h2>
<h3 id="parquetcourtscontentnausea">Parquet Courts - Content Nausea</h3>
<p>The latest release from Parquet Courts, <a href="https://play.google.com/music/m/Bxrpgmypli632vdxvrg6sx2fec4">Content Nausea</a> has the usual
balance of raucousness and hooks I've come to expect from the Texan band. The title
track is particularly good.</p>
<h3 id="fugazifirstdemo">Fugazi - First Demo</h3>
<p>I don't usually truck with demoes, outtakes, and the like. Music is a craft and
releasing half finished work is anathema to me. Having said that, I was surprised
at how enjoyable it was to listen to <a href="https://play.google.com/music/m/Bmvwiwr2flzwnxdvh4k7indgeze">First Demo</a>.
Fugazi are one of my favourite bands, and to hear them in action before they'd
nailed down their sound is intriguing. The songs are still great, but the
trainspotting to be done here for Fugazi fans is the selling point.</p>]]></description>
            <author>mail@lukehansford.me (Luke Hansford)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ephemera - 7th December, 2014]]></title>
            <link>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2014-12-07/</link>
            <guid>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2014-12-07/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2014 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Well this undertaking has not been as weekly as I would have liked. To try to make up for that, this entry covers two weeks of reading and listening (I watched things, but nothing special enough to recommend).</p>
<h2 id="reading">Reading</h2>
<h3 id="newatheismoldempirebylukesavagejacobinhttpswwwjacobinmagcom201412newatheismoldempire"><a href="https://www.jacobinmag.com/2014/12/new-atheism-old-empire/">New Atheism, Old Empire by Luke Savage - <em>Jacobin</em></a></h3>
<p>As an atheist, I was attracted to Richard Dawkins' <em>The God Delusion</em> when it was released.
I picked it up but couldn't get through it. There was something about it that was, ironically, "holier than thou" when it came to addressing religion - the key trait that put me off organised religion in the first place. Luke Savage addresses this and the inherent racism/islamophobia present in some of the key works of the New Atheism movement.</p>
<p>To me, the best way to further the atheist movement is to make it a more attractive option, not to try and tear down its competitors (a tactic that will often come off as petty). I'm sure there are writers out there that achieve this, but I don't know of any off the top of my head. If you have a recommendation in this regard, I'd love to hear it! In the mean time I'll keep reading the fantastic <em>Jacobin</em>.</p>
<p>Also related:</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"><p>Could be the Best Cartoon Ever <a href="http://t.co/T4uE2sx6Xn">pic.twitter.com/T4uE2sx6Xn</a></p>&mdash; ian bremmer (@ianbremmer) <a href="https://twitter.com/ianbremmer/status/539467697411883011">December 1, 2014</a></blockquote>
<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
<h3 id="becausereadingisfundementalbyjeffatwoodcodinghorrorhttpblogcodinghorrorcombecausereadingisfundamental2"><a href="http://blog.codinghorror.com/because-reading-is-fundamental-2/">Because Reading is Fundemental by Jeff Atwood - <em>Coding Horror</em></a></h3>
<p>Jeff Atwood, a.k.a <em>Coding Horror</em>, is the best there is when it comes to analysing and building for online communities. For proof look no further than the (Stack Exchange)[www.stackexchange.com] network he founded. In this article he argues for changing the metric for good online commenters from number of comments to time spent reading, or at the very least incentivising people to spend more time reading before posting.</p>
<h2 id="listening">Listening</h2>
<h3 id="rustiegreenlanguagehttpsplaygooglecomstoremusicalbumrustie_green_languageidbcvjixyaj4luml2n6nuweojvrd4"><a href="https://play.google.com/store/music/album/Rustie_Green_Language?id=Bcvjixyaj4luml2n6nuweojvrd4">Rustie - Green Language</a></h3>
<p>I was listening to this a lot when it first came out in August, but I'm also listening to it now while writing this blog post, so I figured a recommendation was in order. I love electronic music, but I there's no way I'll ever be able to keep up with the ever proliferating array of subgenres. I think Rustie is considered <em>Maximalist Dubstep</em>. Influences are present - I personally hear Air, 808 State, The Bug, and Skream, among others - but rather than taking small aspects of each, Rustie takes the whole thing and melds them together to create a sound that is big, but alway coherent.</p>
<h3 id="startuppodcasthttpgimletmediacom"><a href="http://gimletmedia.com/">Startup Podcast</a></h3>
<p>I'd been hearing about the Startup podcast for a while now. The premise, a podcast detailing the creating of a podcast network, was intriguing to me. I'm currently a dozen episode into <a href="http://frequency.asia">my own podcast</a>, and harbour secret/evil dreams of transforming it into a network of podcasts in the vein of Radiotopia or 5by5. But I was hesitant to add another podcast to my already overly large regime. One day I'm going to have more podcasts then time to listen to them.</p>
<p>I eventually gave in, and it was well worth. Alex Blumberg is extremely candid and transparent in his coverage of the creation of Gimlet Media. While the creation of a new media network is the core topic, the podcast veers into areas such as startup culture, the creative process, and the feelings and thoughts of people taking great leaps of faith. Not only have I added this podcast to the myriad of others I listen to, if the other podcasts they plan on releasing are of this quality then I'm definitely going to be listening to them too. Crap.</p>]]></description>
            <author>mail@lukehansford.me (Luke Hansford)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ephemera - 14th December, 2014]]></title>
            <link>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2014-12-14/</link>
            <guid>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2014-12-14/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2014 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Short and sweet as I'm going to Vietnam in a few hours. I most likely won't be able to post anything for two weeks, so you'll have to subsist on end of year lists in the mean time.</p>
<h2 id="reading">Reading</h2>
<h3 id="thenewrepublicanappreciationbytanehisicoatestheatlantichttpwwwtheatlanticcompoliticsarchive201412thenewrepublicanappreciation383561"><a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2014/12/the-new-republic-an-appreciation/383561/">The New Republic: An Appreciation by Ta-Nehisi Coates - <em>The Atlantic</em></a></h3>
<p>I've only ever read New Republic articles here and there, so I wouldn't say that I'm effected by the troubles occurring with the publication these days. I'm even less troubled having read the ever brilliant Coates' skewering of the magazine and its record in regards to race.</p>
<h3 id="qassemsuleimanibymartinchulovtheguardianhttpwwwtheguardiancomtheobserver2014dec07qassemsuleimanimiddleeastmastermindislamicstate"><a href="http://www.theguardian.com/theobserver/2014/dec/07/qassem-suleimani-middle-east-mastermind-islamic-state">Qassem Suleimani by Martin Chulov - <em>The Guardian</em></a></h3>
<p>A great profile on the leader of Iranian military efforts in the Middle East. I feel that it's rare to see articles in mainstream publications that address the realpolitik involved in the region and not collapse into apocalyptic rhetoric.</p>
<h3 id="inconversationwithchrisrockbyfrankrichvulturehttpwwwvulturecom201411chrisrockfrankrichinconversationhtml"><a href="http://www.vulture.com/2014/11/chris-rock-frank-rich-in-conversation.html">In Conversation With Chris Rock by Frank Rich - <em>Vulture</em></a></h3>
<p>An impressive interview with an impressive man.</p>
<h2 id="viewing">Viewing</h2>
<h3 id="xkcd1411httpxkcdcom1411"><a href="http://xkcd.com/1411/">XKCD 1411</a></h3>
<p>The story of my life.</p>
<p><img src="http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/loop.png" alt="XKCD 1411" title="XKCD 1411" /></p>
<h3 id="supernormalstimulibystuartmcmillenhttpwwwstuartmcmillencomcomics_ensupernormalstimuli"><a href="http://www.stuartmcmillen.com/comics_en/supernormal-stimuli/">Supernormal Stimuli by Stuart McMillen</a></h3>
<p>Just a nice comic reminding me that I have a lizard brain sometimes.</p>
<h3 id="2014theyearinphotosseptemberdecemberbyalantaylortheatlantichttpwwwtheatlanticcominfocus2014122014theyearinphotosseptemberdecember100870"><a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/infocus/2014/12/2014-the-year-in-photos-september-december/100870/">2014: The Year in Photos, September-December by Alan Taylor - <em>The Atlantic</em></a></h3>
<p>Part 3 in a round up of photos from 2014. It's good to have such a vivid refresher on what happened in the last 12 months.</p>
<p><img src="http://cdn.theatlantic.com/static/infocus/yip121014/s_y18_57212566.jpg" alt="Protest in Hong Kong" title="Protests in Hong Kong" /></p>
<h2 id="listening">Listening</h2>
<h3 id="thepodcastmethodhttppodcastmethodco"><a href="http://podcastmethod.co/">The Podcast Method</a></h3>
<p>Dan Benjamin of 5by5 has just started a new podcast about how to podcast. Meta. I'm 13 episdoes in to my own podcast, <a href="http://frequency.asia">Frequency Asia</a>, so I'm finding it fantastically useful so far.</p>]]></description>
            <author>mail@lukehansford.me (Luke Hansford)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ephemera - 4th January, 2015]]></title>
            <link>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2015-01-04/</link>
            <guid>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2015-01-04/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2015 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>There hasn't been a lot of new things to see, read, or hear in the last few weeks, being the holiday season and all. Here is what I scrounged up.</p>
<h2 id="reading">Reading</h2>
<h3 id="themartianbyandyweir">The Martian by Andy Weir</h3>
<p>This self-published novel is possibly the best book I read in 2014. I had just
finished up Kim Stanley Robinson's Mars Trilogy, which were also excellent reads,
and was lucky to have The Martian waiting next to keep my Mars bender going. Andy
Weir takes the Robinson Crusoe trope and realistically applies it to an astronaut
on Mars. Not only does Weir make it a believable conceit, he manages to make it
 a compelling read too.</p>
<h3 id="thetragedyoftheamericanmilitarybyjamesfallowstheatlantichttpwwwtheatlanticcomfeaturesarchive201412thetragedyoftheamericanmilitary383516"><a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/features/archive/2014/12/the-tragedy-of-the-american-military/383516/">The Tragedy of the American Military by James Fallows - <em>The Atlantic</em></a></h3>
<p>I'll read anything by James Fallows, but a screed on the role of the armed forces
in American society and how a public and political disconnect with them has led to
rampant militarism? Sign me up.</p>
<h2 id="watching">Watching</h2>
<h3 id="webuiltadronebygregormaclennandigitaldemocracyhttpwwwdigitaldemocracyorgblogwebuiltadrone"><a href="http://www.digital-democracy.org/blog/we-built-a-drone/">We Built A Drone by Gregor MacLennan - <em>Digital Democracy</em></a></h3>
<p>Using drones to empower citizens in indigenous communities in Guyana. It's nice to
have this as a counterpoint to the use of drones for warfare.</p>]]></description>
            <author>mail@lukehansford.me (Luke Hansford)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ephemera - 1st February, 2015]]></title>
            <link>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2015-02-01/</link>
            <guid>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2015-02-01/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>I've been letting this slide for the last few weeks, so time for a roundup of what I've been consuming and enjoying .</p>
<h2 id="reading">Reading</h2>
<h3 id="tenyearsofpodcastingfightinghumannaturebymatthaugheyhttpsmediumcomtechnologymusingstenyearsofpodcastingfightinghumannature1bf2de96d6e4"><a href="https://medium.com/technology-musings/ten-years-of-podcasting-fighting-human-nature-1bf2de96d6e4">Ten Years of Podcasting: Fighting Human Nature by Matt Haughey</a></h3>
<p>Great commentary on the state of podcasting a decade in. Matt Haughey has a number of suggestions
for how we can improve the technological aspects or podcasts, most of which I, as a podcaster,
completely agree with. My hope is that we start to see some of these appear soon. Haughey
also wrote a nice follow up article to this one, so give that a go to.</p>
<h3 id="theyearsofriceandsaltbykimstanleyrobinson">The Years of Rice and Salt by Kim Stanley Robinson</h3>
<p>Alternate history is not usually in my wheelhouse (actual history is compelling
enough for me), but Robinson's epic tale of a world where Europe is wiped out by
the Black Plague is much more than your standard alternate history novel. With
the Buddhist concept of reincarnation at its core, <em>The Years of Rice and Salt</em>
follows a number of characters through different reincarnations over the centuries.
Each life allows Robinson to play with the form of his writing and inject cutting
social, religious, and political commentary into the story, making for a enjoyable,
if difficult at times, read.</p>
<h2 id="listening">Listening</h2>
<h3 id="twerpsrangeanxiety">Twerps - Range Anxiety</h3>
<p>Labelled dolecore by some commentators, Twerps to me are tapping in to a uniquely antipodean vein of music with forbearers in
the Go-Betweens or the Dunedin bands of the 1980s. Range Anxiety is a really strong
second album from this Melbourne band, and while I've only had it a day or two I
wholeheartedly recommend it.</p>]]></description>
            <author>mail@lukehansford.me (Luke Hansford)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ephemera - 15th January, 2018]]></title>
            <link>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2018-01-15/</link>
            <guid>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2018-01-15/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>It's been a while since I've done an entry here. I'm going to start dipping a toe back into 
blogging, beginning with writing these old weekly round-ups! I doubt anyone is reading at the moment, 
but it's a nice little thing to do for posterity's sake.</p>
<h2 id="reading">Reading</h2>
<h3 id="the25bestreissuesandretrospectivesof2017httpwwwfactmagcom20171210bestreissues2017"><a href="http://www.factmag.com/2017/12/10/best-reissues-2017/">The 25 best reissues and retrospectives of 2017</a></h3>
<p>January is always reserved for listening to year ends lists for me, and the Factmag ones this year are killer. 
Top picks from this list for me are Midori Takada's <em>Through The Looking Glass</em>, Metro Area's self-titled release, 
and number one pick <em>Noir Et Blanc</em>.</p>
<h3 id="makeanalogsynthesizershttpswwwamazoncommakeanalogsynthesizerselectronicsynthdiydp1449345220"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Make-Analog-Synthesizers-Electronic-Synth-DIY/dp/1449345220">Make: Analog Synthesizers</a></h3>
<p>I've been picking up some DIY electronics skills over the last few months, and I've decided to dive into 
building my own synthesizer with this book as a guide. I'm still waiting on the parts to arrive so I 
can get started, but in the meantime it's a wonderful introduction into the inner workings of an electronic instrument.</p>]]></description>
            <author>mail@lukehansford.me (Luke Hansford)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ephemera - 29th January, 2018]]></title>
            <link>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2018-01-29/</link>
            <guid>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2018-01-29/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<h2 id="reading">Reading</h2>
<h3 id="theline6dl4isquietlythemostimportantguitarpedalofthelast20yearshttpspitchforkcomthepitchtheline6dl4isquietlythemostimportantguitarpedalofthelast20years"><a href="https://pitchfork.com/thepitch/the-line-6-dl4-is-quietly-the-most-important-guitar-pedal-of-the-last-20-years/">The Line 6 DL4 Is Quietly the Most Important Guitar Pedal of the Last 20 Years</a></h3>
<p>A really interesting article on a guitar pedal I always dismissed as plastic trash. For some reason Line6
products have always put me off, but apparently a lot of my favourite artists knew better. Battles have used over a dozen of them!</p>
<h3 id="onbeinganengineeringmanagerhttpcodepleaseio20180115onbeinganengineeringmanager"><a href="http://codeplease.io/2018/01/15/on-being-an-engineering-manager/">On being an Engineering Manager</a></h3>
<p>I'm not quite an engineering manager - being one member of a team of two makes that a little hard - however over the last year I have been transitioning into a role that includes certain responsibilities that an engineering manager would need to take on. Rui Peres has also been making that transition and he gives some nice insights into the trials and tribulations that can pop up.</p>
<h3 id="therealfutureofworkhttpswwwpoliticocommagazinestory20180104futureworkindependentcontractorsalternativeworkarrangements216212"><a href="https://www.politico.com/magazine/story/2018/01/04/future-work-independent-contractors-alternative-work-arrangements-216212">The Real Future of Work</a></h3>
<p>This article makes the argument that the gig economy is just another step in the ongoing erosion of 
worker's rights and is in itself nothing particularly new. An in-depth look into an issue that is 
likely going to be one of the defining social changes of the 21st century.</p>
<h2 id="watching">Watching</h2>
<h3 id="whywebleeppodcast001tomwhitwellhttpswwwyoutubecomwatchvn18ro8nxxi4"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=N18ro8nxXI4">Why We Bleep Podcast 001: Tom Whitwell</a></h3>
<p>Oh yes! Mylar Melodies, one of my favourite synth YouTubers, has just started a long-form 
interview series talking to the people behind electronic instruments. The first episode features the 
wonderful Tom Whitwell aka Music Thing Modular.</p>
<h3 id="howtomakeaeurorackmodulehttpswwwyoutubecomwatchv0fwpu4bjrm4t13s"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0fWPu4BjRM4&t=13s">How to Make a Eurorack Module</a></h3>
<p>Another one from the Mylar Melodies YouTube channel, though this one is just a recording of a talk 
given by James Carruthers of NoBots. The talk walks through the process of designing and shipping a 
Eurorack module and I think it may have planted a seed in me to do one myself some day.</p>]]></description>
            <author>mail@lukehansford.me (Luke Hansford)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ephemera - 5th February, 2018]]></title>
            <link>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2018-02-05/</link>
            <guid>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2018-02-05/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<h2 id="reading">Reading</h2>
<h3 id="howireviewcodehttpsengineeringtumblrcompost170040992289howireviewcode"><a href="https://engineering.tumblr.com/post/170040992289/how-i-review-code">How I review code</a></h3>
<p>A Tumblr engineer walks through his process for code reviews. I found this pretty instructive as I'm 
currently in the middle of trying to come to grips with formalising code reviews in my own company.</p>
<h2 id="listening">Listening</h2>
<h3 id="labratxlmiceorcyborg">Lab Rat XL ‎- Mice Or Cyborg</h3>
<p>This 2003 album just got a re-release and I've been listening to it all week while coding. Lab Rat XL
was a side project of Detroit Techno legends Drexciya, and this release was one of their last before the 
passing of James Stinson, one half of the duo. The tracks slot in nicely to the Drexciya ouvre of minimal-ish 
afrofuturist techno.</p>]]></description>
            <author>mail@lukehansford.me (Luke Hansford)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ephemera - 12th February, 2018]]></title>
            <link>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2018-02-12/</link>
            <guid>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2018-02-12/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<h2 id="reading">Reading</h2>
<h3 id="theriseofchinaandthefallofthefreetrademythhttpswwwnytimescom20180207magazinetheriseofchinaandthefallofthefreetrademythhtml"><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/02/07/magazine/the-rise-of-china-and-the-fall-of-the-free-trade-myth.html">The Rise of China and the Fall of the ‘Free Trade’ Myth</a></h3>
<p>Pankaj Mishra is an author I always love to read so it was nice to stumble upon this NY Times Magazine
article from him. It's a divisive but intriguing take on the economic rise of the great nations. From my
on the ground experience in China I feel like he might be paving over some of the more free-wheeling capitalistic
tendencies that can be found in China at the moment or in the last two decades, but in general I'd agree with 
his main assertions.</p>
<h3 id="principlesofadultbehaviourhttpsgistgithubcomhernamesbarbarac647b18411157205edffcb94db0bcea8"><a href="https://gist.github.com/hernamesbarbara/c647b18411157205edffcb94db0bcea8">Principles of Adult Behaviour</a></h3>
<p>With the passing this week of John Perry Barlow, this list of "life lessons" seemed quite apt.</p>
<h2 id="watching">Watching</h2>
<h3 id="alteredcarbonhttpswwwnetflixcomtitle80097140"><a href="https://www.netflix.com/title/80097140">Altered Carbon</a></h3>
<p>Damn this show was awesome. The story is a little weak at some points, but they absolutely
nailed the cyber-punk aesthetic and the acting is pretty top notch all around. Highly recommended.</p>
<h3 id="eevblog186solderingtutorialpart3surfacemounthttpswwwyoutubecomwatchvb9fc9falfqeappdesktop"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=b9FC9fAlfQE&app=desktop">EEVblog #186 - Soldering Tutorial Part 3 - Surface Mount</a></h3>
<p>Just a great video on how to surface mount solder. I've got a Hot Air Rework station sitting in my workshop ready for its
first use and I've been feeling a bit nervous about it. This tutorial has definitely helped to allay some of those worries.</p>]]></description>
            <author>mail@lukehansford.me (Luke Hansford)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ephemera - 5th March, 2018]]></title>
            <link>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2018-03-05/</link>
            <guid>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2018-03-05/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>I missed a few weeks there - Chinese New Year has a tendency to disrupt my routines - but I'm back at it now!</p>
<h2 id="reading">Reading</h2>
<h3 id="the100yearcapitalistexperimentthatkeepsappalachiapoorsickandstuckoncoalhttpsqzcom1167671the100yearcapitalistexperimentthatkeepsappalachiapoorsickandstuckoncoal"><a href="https://qz.com/1167671/the-100-year-capitalist-experiment-that-keeps-appalachia-poor-sick-and-stuck-on-coal/">The 100-year capitalist experiment that keeps Appalachia poor, sick, and stuck on coal</a></h3>
<p>I find the economics and politics of the United States endlessly fascinating. It's such a kaleidoscope of
views, opinions, and histories. This article targets the political history of the Appalachian region
of the US. If you find this interesting check out the book "Dreamland" by Sam Quinones. It focuses on
the ongoing opioid epidemic in the US, but similar themes as found in this article pop up all over the place.</p>
<h3 id="bandcamphttpsdailybandcampcom20180212thebandcamp2017yearinreview"><a href="https://daily.bandcamp.com/2018/02/12/the-bandcamp-2017-year-in-review/">Bandcamp</a></h3>
<p>Yay for Bandcamp! For me it's the one major web company that has only had a purely positive impact
on the communities it is involved with (feel free to prove me wrong, I'm sure I'm forgetting some other companies).
It's great to see them continuing to grow.</p>
<h3 id="thedonkeykongtimelineistrulydisturbinghttpskotakucomthedonkeykongtimelineistrulydisturbing1823035151"><a href="https://kotaku.com/the-donkey-kong-timeline-is-truly-disturbing-1823035151">The Donkey Kong Timeline Is Truly Disturbing</a></h3>
<p>Some people have too much time on their hands, and I'm very glad for that.</p>
<h2 id="listening">Listening</h2>
<h3 id="aalagainstalllogic20122017httpswwwdiscogscomartist3754267aalagainstalllogic"><a href="https://www.discogs.com/artist/3754267-AAL-Against-All-Logic">A.A.L. (Against All Logic) - 2012-2017</a></h3>
<p>I can't remember the last time I felt this way listening to house music. A.A.L. (bka Nicolas Jaar)
has tapped into the rawness at the core of house, a rawness that has been missing from most house music
I've heard in the last decade (with the big caveat that I don't listen to much house).</p>]]></description>
            <author>mail@lukehansford.me (Luke Hansford)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ephemera - 5th April, 2018]]></title>
            <link>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2018-04-05/</link>
            <guid>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2018-04-05/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Well I broke the chain again, though to be honest it was more just to a lack of anything to talk about rather
than procrastinating/forgetting to write something like usual.</p>
<h2 id="reading">Reading</h2>
<h3 id="provenancebyannleckiehttpswwwamazoncomprovenanceannleckieebookdpb06xw6ytkvrefasap_bcieutf8"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Provenance-Ann-Leckie-ebook/dp/B06XW6YTKV/ref=asap_bc?ie=UTF8">Provenance by Ann Leckie</a></h3>
<p>I spotted this on this year's Hugo Awards shortlist; I had no idea that Leckie has a new book out already, so it was a pleasant surprise.
I'm only about halfway through it, but Provenance is so far proving to be of the same calibre as the Ancillary series, with the same world-building that has a way of making you question your own preconceptions about society.</p>
<h3 id="allriseandnofallhowcivilizationreinforcesadangerousmythhttpswwwrockpapershotguncom20180315allriseandnofallhowcivilizationreinforcesadangerousmyth"><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/2018/03/15/all-rise-and-no-fall-how-civilization-reinforces-a-dangerous-myth/">All rise and no fall: how Civilization reinforces a dangerous myth</a></h3>
<p>As a strategy game fiend and someone who sits very much on the political left, this article hit very close to home for me. A lot of
historical strategy games ascribe strongly to the "great men" view of history, paving over the realities of the eras they're set in. But it's of course a tricky situation for developer who must balance historicity with fun, and it seems to be a rather large challenge simulating the fall of a player's empire. As an aside, the article offer Crusader Kings 2 as a good example of an alternative to Civilization's growth at all costs mentality, but I'd suggest another game from Paradox, Victoria 2 as a better example - it's simulation of communist or fascist uprisings, or the brutality of an economic depression show a path where a player can lose almost all they've built up but still have the opportunity to turn it around and "win" the game.</p>
<h3 id="stephenhawking19422018httpsjacobinmagcom201803stephenhawkingobituaryalsnhsbds"><a href="https://jacobinmag.com/2018/03/stephen-hawking-obituary-als-nhs-bds">Stephen Hawking (1942–2018)</a></h3>
<p>There were lots of great obituaries for the great scientist Stephen Hawking, but I found this one particularly interesting due to 
it's insight into Hawking's political activism, an area of his life that I was unaware of.</p>]]></description>
            <author>mail@lukehansford.me (Luke Hansford)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ephemera - 6th May, 2018]]></title>
            <link>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2018-05-06/</link>
            <guid>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2018-05-06/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Today I've got a bunch of short recommendations as I've been procrastinating compiling them for the last few weeks.</p>
<h2 id="reading">Reading</h2>
<h3 id="howreferendumsbreakdemocraciesbytimharfordhttptimharfordcom201803howreferendumsbreakdemocracies"><a href="http://timharford.com/2018/03/how-referendums-break-democracies/">How referendums break democracies by Tim Harford</a></h3>
<p>Tim Harford is an economics author who I keep returning to as a small dose of sanity in the chaotic political atmosphere
of the last few years.</p>
<h3 id="howtowriteagitcommitmessagebychrisbeamshttpschrisbeamsiopostsgitcommit"><a href="https://chris.beams.io/posts/git-commit/">How to Write a Git Commit Message by Chris Beams</a></h3>
<p>Sage advice for the coders among you. I revisited this article while rewriting the code quality guideline for the company 
I work for. Commits messages are a simple thing on the face of it, but doing them correctly can make a massive difference
to communication in a development team.</p>
<h3 id="whatidontlikeaboutcapitalismpartibydaveruperthttpsdaverupertcom201804whatidontlikeaboutcapitalismparti"><a href="https://daverupert.com/2018/04/what-i-don-t-like-about-capitalism-part-i/">What I Don't Like About Capitalism (Part I) by Dave Rupert</a></h3>
<p>Written from a tech workers perspective. I'm only partially on board with the thesis as I believe the denigration "low-quality goods and services" can be an overly simplified argument that ignores economic imbalances on a global scale, but I still think Dave make a generally good point in the article.</p>
<h3 id="ataxonomyoftechnicaldebthttpsengineeringriotgamescomnewstaxonomytechdebt"><a href="https://engineering.riotgames.com/news/taxonomy-tech-debt">A Taxonomy of Technical Debt</a></h3>
<p>This article is no fucking joke. I immediately forwarded it to the entire tech team at my office. The author has, in my
opinion, nailed the nebulous concept that is technical debt.</p>
<h3 id="anengineersbillofrightsandresponsibilitiesbycharitymajorshttpscharitywtf20180330anengineersbillofrightsandresponsibilities"><a href="https://charity.wtf/2018/03/30/an-engineers-bill-of-rights-and-responsibilities/">An Engineer's Bill of Rights (And Responsibilities) by Charity Majors</a></h3>
<p>Not much to say on this other than give it a read if you're a software engineer.</p>
<h3 id="thelatesttrendfortechinterviewsdaysofunpaidhomeworkhttpsworkqzcom1254663jobinterviewsforprogrammersnowoftencomewithdaysofunpaidhomework"><a href="https://work.qz.com/1254663/job-interviews-for-programmers-now-often-come-with-days-of-unpaid-homework/">The latest trend for tech interviews: Days of unpaid homework</a></h3>
<p>Oh man, this article hit me hard. I'm currently sitting on both sides of the fence of this "trend", having experienced such
requests in my current job search, while also giving out such assignments while trying to hire for my current company. I have
to admit that I haven't previously thought to hard on how requesting chunks of time from a job applicant can make the playing field
uneven, and, after reading this article (and the Hacker News discussion around it) I'm definitely going to be working on changing our hiring process in my current job before I move on.</p>
<h3 id="estimationisacorecompetencybyginatrapanihttpstrackchangespostlightcomestimationisacorecompetency36dfc1dfdea3"><a href="https://trackchanges.postlight.com/estimation-is-a-core-competency-36dfc1dfdea3">Estimation Is a Core Competency by Gina Trapani</a></h3>
<p>Gina Trapani calls out the bullshit "estimation is impossible" argument that every dev has been guilty of making at some point in time (myself included).</p>
<h3 id="theunitedstatesofjapanhttpswwwnewyorkercomcultureculturedesktheunitedstatesofjapan"><a href="https://www.newyorker.com/culture/culture-desk/the-united-states-of-japan">The United States of Japan</a></h3>]]></description>
            <author>mail@lukehansford.me (Luke Hansford)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ephemera - 17th June, 2018]]></title>
            <link>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2018-06-17/</link>
            <guid>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2018-06-17/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<h2 id="reading">Reading</h2>
<h3 id="utcisenoughforeveryonerighthttpszachholmancomtalkutcisenoughforeveryoneright"><a href="https://zachholman.com/talk/utc-is-enough-for-everyone-right">UTC is enough for everyone…right?</a></h3>
<p>A great article and great web design is always a killer combo. Also a timely (yeah, pun intended) reminder of why 
time is one of the more complex areas of computer science.</p>
<h3 id="fridayfacts246theguiupdatepart3httpswwwfactoriocomblogpostfff246"><a href="https://www.factorio.com/blog/post/fff-246">Friday Facts #246 - The GUI update (Part 3)</a></h3>
<p>I've not played Factorio before, but even so I loved this deep dive into the surprisingly complicated 
issue of button placement in application UIs. The <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17269938">Hacker News conversation</a> about this article is equally informative</p>]]></description>
            <author>mail@lukehansford.me (Luke Hansford)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ephemera - 24th June, 2018]]></title>
            <link>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2018-06-24/</link>
            <guid>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2018-06-24/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<h2 id="reading">Reading</h2>
<h3 id="whathedoeswithwhathehasblawaninterviewedhttpthequietuscomarticles24794blawanjamierobertsinterview"><a href="http://thequietus.com/articles/24794-blawan-jamie-roberts-interview">What He Does With What He Has: Blawan Interviewed</a></h3>
<p>Like most people I became familiar with Blawan after hearing 'Why They Hide Their Bodies Under My Garage', and his subsequent
disappearance from the musical landscape always left me wanting more. This interview with The Quietus
explains where he went to, and how he evolved from the frantic horror-dubstep of his earlier releases to the oddly-organic
minimal techno he's making nowadays.</p>
<h3 id="theradicallessonsofayearreportingonknifecrimehttpswwwtheguardiancommembership2018jun21radicallessonsknifecrimebeyondtheblade"><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/membership/2018/jun/21/radical-lessons-knife-crime-beyond-the-blade">The radical lessons of a year reporting on knife crime</a></h3>
<p>A fascinating look into the facts and perceptions of knife crime in the UK. Particularly interesting
are the parallels between violence and infectious disease, and how treating crime as a public health 
issue can yield results.</p>
<h2 id="listening">Listening</h2>
<h3 id="blawanwetwillalwaysdry">Blawan - Wet Will Always Dry</h3>
<p>See the reading recommendation above! Excellently tailored minimal/industrial techno.</p>]]></description>
            <author>mail@lukehansford.me (Luke Hansford)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ephemera - 1st July, 2018]]></title>
            <link>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2018-07-01/</link>
            <guid>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2018-07-01/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<h2 id="reading">Reading</h2>
<h3 id="memorizingthesethreestatisticswillhelpyouunderstandtheworldhttpswwwgatesnotescomdevelopmentmaxroserthreefactseveryoneshouldknow"><a href="https://www.gatesnotes.com/Development/Max-Roser-three-facts-everyone-should-know">Memorizing these three statistics will help you understand the world</a></h3>
<p>The title is a little clickbait-y (though that's pretty run-of-the-mill these days), but the article
itself is still worthy. Essentially it's a bunch of statistics, and pretty well known ones at that, but
it is nice to have a condensed reminder of the positive changes humanity has made in the last century
and offset the general pessimism that seems to be the trend at the moment.</p>]]></description>
            <author>mail@lukehansford.me (Luke Hansford)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ephemera - 2nd September, 2018]]></title>
            <link>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2018-09-02/</link>
            <guid>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2018-09-02/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<h2 id="reading">Reading</h2>
<h3 id="annoyedbyrestaurantplaylistsamastermusicianmadehisownhttpswwwnytimescom20180723diningrestaurantmusicplaylistsryuichisakamotohtml"><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/07/23/dining/restaurant-music-playlists-ryuichi-sakamoto.html">Annoyed by Restaurant Playlists, a Master Musician Made His Own</a></h3>
<p>This article feels like peak-Ryuichi Sakamoto. Good background music will make me return to an average restaraunt or bar every time. And that playlist is ace - it warms my heart to know he's a fan of both Aphex Twin and Oneohtrix Point Never.</p>
<h3 id="themysteriousheartoftherolandtr808drummachinehttpsecretlifeofsynthesizerscomthestrangeheartoftherolandtr808"><a href="http://secretlifeofsynthesizers.com/the-strange-heart-of-the-roland-tr-808/">The mysterious heart of the Roland TR-808 drum machine</a></h3>
<p>I often thought of electronics as being made up of stolid, identical components, but over the last year I've learnt how different two instances of the same IC can be. Turns out the classic TR808 drum machine uses these "defective" ICs to its advantage</p>
<h2 id="watching">Watching</h2>
<h3 id="whywebleep006scannerhttpswwwwhywebleepcomwhywebleep201830whywebleep006"><a href="https://www.whywebleep.com/whywebleep/2018/30/whywebleep006">WHY WE BLEEP 006: SCANNER</a></h3>
<p>This interview was not exactly what I expected. A lot less music tech geekery and a lot more in the way of philosophies on life. I've been trying to journal ever since watching it, though to be honest I haven't been doing very well!</p>]]></description>
            <author>mail@lukehansford.me (Luke Hansford)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ephemera - 23rd September, 2018]]></title>
            <link>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2018-09-23/</link>
            <guid>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2018-09-23/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<h2 id="reading">Reading</h2>
<h3 id="howtodealwithdirtysideeffectsinyourpurefunctionaljavascripthttpsjrsinclaircomarticles2018howtodealwithdirtysideeffectsinyourpurefunctionaljavascript"><a href="https://jrsinclair.com/articles/2018/how-to-deal-with-dirty-side-effects-in-your-pure-functional-javascript/">How To Deal with Dirty Side Effects in Your Pure Functional Javascript</a></h3>
<p>This is a great intro to a more intermediate level of functional programming in JS (and maybe just FP in general). Functors, monads, and general removal of side effects. The tie in with Tensorflow at the end is nice too! I've started a new job in the last month were
the main language I write in is Ruby. While there are touches of functional programming style, it is mostly classic OOP, and
it's made me very quickly appreciate how suited Javascript could be for functional programming if you use a little bit of
coding discipline.</p>]]></description>
            <author>mail@lukehansford.me (Luke Hansford)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ephemera - 1st October, 2018]]></title>
            <link>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2018-10-01/</link>
            <guid>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2018-10-01/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<h2 id="watching">Watching</h2>
<h3 id="buildingimpossibleprogramshttpsjvnscablog20180918buildimpossibleprograms"><a href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2018/09/18/build-impossible-programs/">Building Impossible Programs</a></h3>
<p>Julia Evans does a great talk about building a Ruby profiler. It's a nice reminder that just because an app/tool/program doesn't exist, doesn't mean that it can't be built!</p>]]></description>
            <author>mail@lukehansford.me (Luke Hansford)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ephemera - 19th January, 2019]]></title>
            <link>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2019-01-19/</link>
            <guid>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2019-01-19/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 13:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<h2 id="reading">Reading</h2>
<h3 id="wehavethetechnologybuildingaeuroracksystemforlivetechnohttpswwwnoiseengineeringusblog201914wehavethetechnologybuildingaeuroracksystemforlivetechno"><a href="https://www.noiseengineering.us/blog/2019/1/4/we-have-the-techno-logy-building-a-eurorack-system-for-live-techno">We have the techno-logy: building a Eurorack system for live techno</a></h3>
<p>Noise Engineering has put together an overview of what you need in a Eurorack system to
make banging techno (with two Basimilus Iteritas Alters of course!). I'm going to be
cribbing some ideas for my setup from here over the coming week.</p>
<h3 id="assortednovelsfromrobertjacksonbennetthttpsenwikipediaorgwikirobert_jackson_bennett"><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_Jackson_Bennett">Assorted novels from Robert Jackson Bennett</a></h3>
<p>Over the holiday period I read 4 novels from American fantasy author Robert Jackson Bennett. I started with
<em>Foundryside</em>, which plays out as a fantasy story parsed through a cyber-punk heist caper. It's a
truely intriguing story and I'm pretty keen to read the next entry in the series later this year.</p>
<p>After that I went back and read Bennett's <em>The Divine Cities</em> trilogy. The worldbuilding here was
also fascinating, delving into elements of colonialism and religion. While the pacing was as tight
as in Foundryside, I still found it an enjoyable read.</p>]]></description>
            <author>mail@lukehansford.me (Luke Hansford)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ephemera - 1st February, 2019]]></title>
            <link>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2019-01-31/</link>
            <guid>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2019-01-31/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<h2 id="reading">Reading</h2>
<h3 id="graduallythensuddenlyhttpswwwlinkedincompulsegraduallysuddenlytimoreilly"><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/gradually-suddenly-tim-o-reilly/">Gradually, Then Suddenly</a></h3>
<p>Tim O'Reilly reviews 10 areas of technology that he expects to see breakthroughs in over
coming years. It's a quick read, but one that'll probably inspire you in one way or another.
I'm particularly intrigued by the agricultural technologies he discusses, and that's rabbit hole
I'm now currently going down.</p>
<h2 id="listening">Listening</h2>
<h3 id="demdikestarestitchbystitchtape4httpssoundcloudcommodernlovedemdikestarestitchbystitchtape4"><a href="https://soundcloud.com/modernlove/demdike-stare-stitch-by-stitch-tape-4">Demdike Stare - Stitch By Stitch Tape 4</a></h3>
<p>Turns out that Demdike Stare put out four tape mixes of dark dubby drones last year
(on top of the excellent album Passion). It's been my work soundtrack all week.</p>
<h3 id="variouslifedeathonthenewyorkdancefloor19801983partiiihttpswwwresidentadvisornetreviews23381"><a href="https://www.residentadvisor.net/reviews/23381">Various - Life & Death On The New York Dance Floor 1980-1983 Part I & II</a></h3>
<blockquote>
  <p>"I was there in the Paradise Garage DJ booth with Larry Levan" - LCD Soundsystem - Losing My Edge</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The 80s NY disco scene is a musical era I'd heard spoken of before, but not one I'd ever explored
much besides the peripheries were it crossed over into New Wave or other 80s electronic movements. This
compilation definitely make me want to learn more about it though. The sounds here really bridge the
gap between New York new/no wave bands of the same time and the kind of music that was soon to be made for the clubs of
Detroit and Chicago (and later, Manchester).</p>]]></description>
            <author>mail@lukehansford.me (Luke Hansford)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ephemera - 30th May, 2019]]></title>
            <link>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2019-05-30/</link>
            <guid>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2019-05-30/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<h2 id="reading">Reading</h2>
<h3 id="typescript30theunknowntypehttpsmariusschulzcomblogtypescript30theunknowntype"><a href="https://mariusschulz.com/blog/typescript-3-0-the-unknown-type">TypeScript 3.0: The unknown Type</a></h3>
<p>I'm immediately going to start using the <code>unknown</code> type in my TypeScript projects after learning
about it in this post from @mariusschulz. No more using <code>any</code> when I'm a little unsure of how to
type data coming from the server!</p>
<h3 id="constassertionsarethekillernewtypescriptfeaturehttpsbloglogrocketcomconstassertionsarethekillernewtypescriptfeatureb73451f35802"><a href="https://blog.logrocket.com/const-assertions-are-the-killer-new-typescript-feature-b73451f35802">const assertions are the killer new TypeScript feature</a></h3>
<p>"killer new feature" generally feels too hyperbolic for me, but in this case I kind of agree. We've
been using const assertions at work while building a component library and it massively reduces the
number of interfaces we'd usually write.</p>
<h3 id="buildingthatadmindashboardhttpsmediumcomfishbrainbuildingthatadmindashboard9a24c5fe569"><a href="https://medium.com/fishbrain/building-that-admin-dashboard-9a24c5fe569">Building that admin dashboard</a></h3>
<p>Building admin tools can be surprisingly hard! One of my colleague's at Fishbrain has written a
great blog post on some of the challenges we've faced doing just that.</p>
<h2 id="listening">Listening</h2>
<h3 id="steevioforgottenfutures">[Steevio - Forgotten Futures]</h3>
<p>A Eurorack hero of mine. Steevio's jazzy techno tunes are all the more impressive for knowing that
they're being constructed on the fly.</p>
<h2 id="watching">Watching</h2>
<h3 id="funwithreacthooksmichaeljacksonandryanflorencehttpswwwyoutubecomwatchv1jws7ccuuxw"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1jWS7cCuUXw">Fun with React Hooks - Michael Jackson and Ryan Florence</a></h3>
<p>I really came away from these two talks with a much more comprehensive understanding of React hooks,
plus some great new ideas on how I could use them in my own work.</p>]]></description>
            <author>mail@lukehansford.me (Luke Hansford)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ephemera - 8th December, 2019]]></title>
            <link>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2019-12-08/</link>
            <guid>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2019-12-08/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>I've been a little sporadic with these posts this year. Maybe next year I can be more consistent…or
maybe not.</p>
<h2 id="reading">Reading</h2>
<h3 id="bloodandsoilinnarendramodisindiahttpswwwnewyorkercommagazine20191209bloodandsoilinnarendramodisindia"><a href="https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2019/12/09/blood-and-soil-in-narendra-modis-india">Blood and Soil in Narendra Modi's India</a></h3>
<p>I was aware of Modi's political history, but not quite to the extent that this article lays out. It's
quite terrifying to me that this has become a somewhat normal political situation around the globe in
recent years (I'm thinking of the mass imprisonment of Uighurs and other minorities in China, the
extra-judicial killings that occur in the Philippines, and police brutality and state sponsored violence
occurring in numerous countries at the moment, among other issues).</p>
<h3 id="52thingsilearnedin2019httpsmediumcomfluxxstudionotes52thingsilearnedin20198ee483e6c816"><a href="https://medium.com/fluxx-studio-notes/52-things-i-learned-in-2019-8ee483e6c816">52 things I learned in 2019</a></h3>
<p>I know Tom Whitwell through the Eurorack world for his work as the behind <a href="https://musicthing.co.uk/">Music Thing Modular</a>,
but I've also grown to love his yearly round up of weird things he learnt in the previous year.</p>
<p>A few favourites:</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>The goal of walking 10,000 steps per day may have originated when a Japanese pedometer manufacturer noticed that the 万 symbol (which means 10,000) looks a little like someone walking. The actual health merits of that number ‘have never been validated by research.’</p>
  <p>mobile phones became mainstream in the US in the early 1990s, the murder rate fell sharply. Street drug dealing became less popular, so gang-related turf wars were less common.</p>
  <p>Drunk shopping could be a $45bn /year industry, and only 6% of people regret their drunk purchases.</p>
</blockquote>]]></description>
            <author>mail@lukehansford.me (Luke Hansford)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ephemera - 15th December, 2019]]></title>
            <link>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2019-12-15/</link>
            <guid>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2019-12-15/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<h2 id="reading">Reading</h2>
<h3 id="howwilliamgibsonkeepshissciencefictionrealhttpswwwnewyorkercommagazine20191216howwilliamgibsonkeepshissciencefictionreal"><a href="https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2019/12/16/how-william-gibson-keeps-his-science-fiction-real#">How William Gibson Keeps His Science Fiction Real</a></h3>
<h3 id="thinkinginreacthookshttpswattenbergercomblogreacthooks"><a href="https://wattenberger.com/blog/react-hooks">Thinking in React Hooks</a></h3>]]></description>
            <author>mail@lukehansford.me (Luke Hansford)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ephemera - 28th June, 2020]]></title>
            <link>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2020-06-28/</link>
            <guid>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2020-06-28/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<h2 id="reading">Reading</h2>
<h3 id="formeremployeesaccusecardsagainsthumanityofaracistandsexistofficeculturehttpswwwpolygoncom202062321300435cardsagainsthumanitymaxtemkinreport"><a href="https://www.polygon.com/2020/6/23/21300435/cards-against-humanity-max-temkin-report">Former employees accuse Cards Against Humanity of a racist and sexist office culture</a></h3>
<p>This article goes into the accusations of racism and sexism at Cards Against Humanity, specifically regarding co-founder Max Temkin. While CAH definitely hasn't aged well and I probably wouldn't feel super comfortable playing it these days, this hit me a little hard because for the last few years one of my favourite podcasts has been <a href="http://dobyfriday.com/">Do By Friday</a>, of which Temkin was a co-host.</p>
<p>I'm not one to wring hands too much when a cultural figure is exposed for their wrongdoings - in a world overwhelmed with quality music, film, and other forms of media I don't really see why anyone feels the need to argue that there's nothing wrong with enjoying a R Kelly song or Louis CK bit. But there's something more personal about podcasts that made this hit home a little for me. It was interesting to hear Temkin's co-hosts grapple with the situation in the episode after the revelation (it seems as if he is ghosting everyone?), and I'm glad they addressed it upfront and honestly.</p>
<h3 id="whenfriendsfuckupandsodoihttpswhateverscalzicom20200625whenfriendsfuckupandsodoi"><a href="https://whatever.scalzi.com/2020/06/25/when-friends-fuck-up-and-so-do-i/">When Friends Fuck Up, and So Do I</a></h3>
<p>Sci-fi author John Scalzi wrote this raw and honest post about his possible complicity/complacency in the above situation and a few other similar ones.</p>
<h3 id="twitterthreadonwritingprocesseshttpstwittercommikeduncanstatus1273261668315824134"><a href="https://twitter.com/mikeduncan/status/1273261668315824134">Twitter thread on writing processes</a></h3>
<p>Author/podcaster/historian Mike Duncan lays out his process for writing his books and podcast episodes in this Twitter thread. Basically it boils down to breaking everything into atomic ideas, from book, to chapters, down to paragraphs. I'm looking forward to reading his biography of the Marquis de Lafayette with potential paragraphs such as "Eligible Bachelor!", "Army is fucked", "I'll buy a boat", and "Fuck the Frenchies". For those of you unfamiliar with Mike Duncan, his <a href="https://www.revolutionspodcast.com">Revolutions Podcast</a> is my vote for the best history podcast out there.</p>
<h2 id="listening">Listening</h2>
<h3 id="juneteenthbandcamplistbysurgeonhttpsbuymusicclublistsurgeonbandcampjuneteenthlist"><a href="https://buymusic.club/list/surgeon-bandcamp-juneteenth-list">Juneteenth Bandcamp list by Surgeon</a></h3>
<p>Techno artist Surgeon shares some of his favourite music from Black artists on Bandcamp. The techno recommendations are great (I picked up releases by Claude Young Jr and Robert Hood), but there's some other classics here like Kamasi Washington's 'The Epic', A Guy Called Gerald's 'Black Secret Technology', and Actress' collaboration with the London Contemporary Orchestra.</p>
<h2 id="watching">Watching</h2>
<h3 id="howbarkerbuiltaplatereverbforpercussiveexperimentshttpswwwyoutubecomwatchvc9qpmqhuput127s"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=C9-qpMqhuPU&t=127s">How Barker built a plate reverb for percussive experiments</a></h3>
<p>Barker has been one of my favourite electronic musicians of the last few years. This video goes in to some of his production techniques, specifically the use of physical reverb modelling which seems to be one of secrets behind his unique sound.</p>
<h2 id="givingto">Giving To</h2>
<p>This is a new section for my Ephemera posts. I'm trying to make more of an effort to donate to charities and contribute to society in other ways (I might write an article about that some time), and I thought it'd be nice to share a little about it here.</p>
<h3 id="aboriginallegalservicenswacthttpswwwalsnswactorgau"><a href="https://www.alsnswact.org.au/">Aboriginal Legal Service (NSW/ACT)</a></h3>
<p>The BLM uprisings in the US recently inspired similar action around the world, including in Australia where deaths in custody has long been an issue for Aboriginal Australians. While I'd like to imagine I'd be marching in support if I was back in Australia, I'm currently on the other side of the world. My small contribution has been to give to the ALS (NSW/ACT), the pioneering organisation providing legal support to the Aboriginal community.</p>]]></description>
            <author>mail@lukehansford.me (Luke Hansford)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ephemera - 17th October, 2020]]></title>
            <link>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2020-10-17/</link>
            <guid>http://lukehansford.me/posts/ephemera-2020-10-17/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 18:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<h2 id="reading">Reading</h2>
<h3 id="anhonestreviewofgatsbyhttpscramranhonestreviewofgatsby"><a href="https://cra.mr/an-honest-review-of-gatsby/">An Honest Review of Gatsby</a></h3>
<p>I kind of wish I'd read this article from Sentry before trying to migrate the Fishbrain tech blog from Medium to Gatsby. While there are some cool aspects of Gatsby, the whole "everything is Graphql" approach feels way overkill for a blog.</p>
<h3 id="cityofamsterdamalgorithmregisterhttpsalgoritmeregisteramsterdamnlenairegister"><a href="https://algoritmeregister.amsterdam.nl/en/ai-register/">City of Amsterdam Algorithm Register</a></h3>
<p>I love this concept of an algorithm registry that the City of Amsteram has. Algorithms are a bit of a boogyman, but at the end of the day its just a way of rearranging and transforming data. I'd be curious if anyone knows of apps that do something similar? I'd love to see something like a Facebook or Amazon algorithm registry!</p>
<h3 id="oncallshouldntsuckaguideformanagershttpscharitywtf20201003oncallshouldntsuckaguideformanagers"><a href="https://charity.wtf/2020/10/03/on-call-shouldnt-suck-a-guide-for-managers/">On Call Shouldn’t Suck: A Guide For Managers</a></h3>
<p>Charity Majors is a continual font of knowledge for an inexperienced engineering manager such as myself. While I'm not directly involved in my company's on call setup, I am tangentially involved, and I found this article enlightening. I can definitely see how a poor on call situation could easily death spiral an engineering team. As Charity puts it:</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>And if your on call experience is mandatory and severely life-impacting, and if you don’t take this dead seriously and fix it ASAP? I hope your team will leave you, and go find a place that truly values their time and sleep.</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="listening">Listening</h2>
<h3 id="autechresignhttpsautechrebandcampcomalbumsign"><a href="https://autechre.bandcamp.com/album/sign">Autechre - SIGN</a></h3>
<p>It's Autechre, so you can't go too wrong! It starts off in the vein of their NTS Sessions form a few years back, but pretty quickly dives into ambient-is tunes that I wouldn't necessarily associate the group with. It's lovely stuff though.</p>
<h3 id="scanneranascenthttpsdinorgukalbumanascentdin63"><a href="https://din.org.uk/album/an-ascent-din63">Scanner - An Ascent</a></h3>
<p>I'm mostly familiar with Scanner via his appearances on a bunch of music tech webcasts and his early 90s IDM tracks. His recent work that I'd listened to seemed to be more towards the performance art side of things - something which I appreciate but don't tend to return to much. <em>An Ascent</em>, however, is an amazing collection of ambient soundscapes. I'm all the more impressed that this is done completely on modular.</p>
<p>One thing I've noticed as I've built out my own modular system over the years is that my ears have become trained to identify how sounds were made, thus removing some of the air of mystery that electronic music has. This album, however, is by no means obvious in it's construction, and I think that's why it appeals to me so much at this point in time.</p>]]></description>
            <author>mail@lukehansford.me (Luke Hansford)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NaNoCroSoMo]]></title>
            <link>http://lukehansford.me/posts/nanocrosomo/</link>
            <guid>http://lukehansford.me/posts/nanocrosomo/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2014 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://nanocrosomo.herokuapp.com/">NaNoCroSoMo</a> (National Novel Crowd Sourcing Month) is my take on <a href="http://nanowrimo.org/">NaNoWriMo</a> inspired by the work of those mentioned in the <a href="http://www.theverge.com/2014/11/25/7276157/nanogenmo-robot-author-novel">recent Verge article</a> covering the work of a number of programmers trying to use algorithms to generate novels. My implementation meets somewhere in the middle of these two. Every thirty seconds a computer generated word is added to the story. This word is selected using n-grams taken from the Google Books corpus.
To add a human element, however, anyone can add their own word. Simply type a word and hit enter to add it to the story.</p>
<p>So far the results are mixed. There's no narrative from the computer-generated words, as they are only selected based on the previous two words. I've also come across cases where the language randomly changes (usually at the start of a new sentence). Despite these issues, however, the sentences being produced are somewhat legible. I'm more interested to see what could happen if numerous people are editing it at the same time. Hopefully the web gets a hold of it!</p>]]></description>
            <author>mail@lukehansford.me (Luke Hansford)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Resolutions for 2015]]></title>
            <link>http://lukehansford.me/posts/resolutions-2015/</link>
            <guid>http://lukehansford.me/posts/resolutions-2015/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>I used to be a cynic in regards to new year resolutions. My line of thought was
that if you really wanted to accomplish something you would just go ahead and do
it, not wait until an arbitrary date to begin. Good in theory, but I think I was
missing the point. Although January 1st truly is arbitrary, time itself is a
rather nebulous concept, and having a set date to reflect and gather one's
thoughts is a valuable opportunity.</p>
<p>2014 was a rather good year for me. I earned a Master's degree, got my first job
in the IT industry, moved to Singapore, started a podcast, and travelled to
Vietnam, Penang, and Melbourne for the first time. I already had ideas for the
coming year before sitting down to write this. I'd like to keep growing Frequency
Asia, and travel if I have the chance. I also want to keep pushing my software
development skills and succeed in my new job.</p>
<p>But I also wanted to expand my
horizons into some new areas - things I've dreamed of accomplishing (or even
just attempting) over the years. I decided to make 12 resolutions for 2015;
ostensibly one for each month, but some of them will take a lot more than a
month to achieve, while others might take a much shorter time. I tried to avoid
vague resolutions and stick to more solid goals, so that by the end of the year
I will be able to look back and give a firm yes or no on whether I had completed
that resolution.</p>
<h2 id="learnmalay">Learn Malay</h2>
<p>This is the only resolution I'm making that doesn't have a discrete goal state. Having lived in China for 5 years, I often get asked the question if I am fluent in Mandarin, to which I usually awkwardly reply that I can get by in China. I don't feel comfortable assessing my own language ability (ironic given that I worked as a language teacher for those 5 years, and that my girlfriend is also a language teacher), so instead this resolution will consist of spending each morning studying Malay for 30 minutes. I might not be fluent by the end of the year, but hopefully I will have put in enough effort to converse in Malay.</p>
<h2 id="getatattoo">Get a tattoo</h2>
<p>I'm reserving the right to back out of this one, but it's something I've been considering for a while. I've always joked that I would never get a tattoo due to my fear of needles, but that was just to cover up a deeper concern - indecisiveness. My fear is that I would immediately regret any tattoo I got. Let's see if I can kill that fear.</p>
<h2 id="writeabook">Write a book</h2>
<p>A novel, a short story, something non-fiction, it just has to qualify as a book. It's a pretty big undertaking, but I imagine it'll be worth it.</p>
<h2 id="makeabook">Make a book</h2>
<p>Yes, this is different from the previous resolution. I want to physically bind a book. I plan to make a compilation of interesting articles I read in 2014, print them, then bind them as a book. I'll post more information about this project in the next week or two.</p>
<h2 id="releaseanapp">Release an app</h2>
<p>And make money from it. Capitalistic, yes, but I'd like to see if I could do it. It doesn't need to be a lot, and the app itself could be huge or tiny.</p>
<h2 id="makecandles">Make candles</h2>
<p>This is a DIY project I've been considering for a while. My last room in Beijing was tiny and had little ventilation, so I took to using candles to make it smell a little nicer. Ikea had a range of candles that smelt just like donuts to me. Candles tend to come with more feminine scents, so I'd like to try making candles with some interesting, more stereotypically masculine flavours such as bacon, whiskey, or sawdust.</p>
<h2 id="bedebtfree">Be debt free</h2>
<p>I got so close to paying off my credit card when I moved back to Australia, but the reality of being a uni student set in and the debt started to rise again. It's not a lot of money to be honest, but it's still a good goal to accomplish.</p>
<h2 id="goonalongdistancecyclingtrip">Go on a long-distance cycling trip</h2>
<p>I'm going to be vague on the terms of this one as I'm not really sure of my capabilities. This would likely be a trip from Singapore to somewhere Malaysia, possibly Malacca. The general objective though will be to ride somewhere far enough away from home that I need to get a hotel room.</p>
<h2 id="startabandplayshowsreleasemusic">Start a band, play shows, release music</h2>
<p>I really miss playing guitar in a band, so I hardly even need to make it a resolution. So I've upped the ante to include playing shows and releasing music. That'll keep me on my toes.</p>
<h2 id="getintouchwithpeople">Get in touch with people</h2>
<p>I'm slack when it comes to communicating to people, so I'm going to try and email/message an old friend I haven't spoken to in a while each week of the year (or possibly more).</p>
<h2 id="dontuseelectronicsthirtyminutesbeforeisleep">Don't use electronics thirty minutes before I sleep</h2>
<p>Apparently they're killing me.</p>
<h2 id="makemaps">Make maps</h2>
<p>I've always loved maps. For the last 8 years or so that passion has been channelled into the computer games produced by Paradox Interactive. They make historical grand strategy games such as the Europa Universalis and Crusader Kings series. I've played A LOT of them (between CKII and EUIV I've clocked 1000 hours), so much that I had to delete Steam and swear of games. I still have a map-shaped desire somewhere deep in my cerebral cortex though, so to try and satiate it I want to try and make maps. Like big, wood framed, hang on your wall, maps. My brain is in overdrive just thinking about it (yeah I know, I'm odd).</p>]]></description>
            <author>mail@lukehansford.me (Luke Hansford)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The State of My Resolutions, April 2015]]></title>
            <link>http://lukehansford.me/posts/resolutions-apr-2015/</link>
            <guid>http://lukehansford.me/posts/resolutions-apr-2015/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In order to keep tabs on the progress of my resolutions for 2015, I'm going to try
and do a writeup at the end of each month to see how I've gone.</p>
<h2 id="learnmalay">Learn Malay</h2>
<p>I only missed nine days of study this month. My week point seems to be the weekends, as I missed almost all of them in March.</p>
<h2 id="getatattoo">Get a tattoo</h2>
<p>No progress.</p>
<h2 id="writeabook">Write a book</h2>
<p>No progress.</p>
<h2 id="makeabook">Make a book</h2>
<p>No progress.</p>
<h2 id="releaseanapp">Release an app</h2>
<p>Back to square one on this. Rethinking whether I want to spend time working on Android stuff.</p>
<h2 id="makecandles">Make candles</h2>
<p>No progress.</p>
<h2 id="bedebtfree">Be debt free</h2>
<p>Paid off a chunk of my credit, still a way to go though.</p>
<h2 id="goonalongdistancecyclingtrip">Go on a long-distance cycling trip</h2>
<p>No progress.</p>
<h2 id="startabandplayshowsreleasemusic">Start a band, play shows, release music</h2>
<p>No progress.</p>
<h2 id="getintouchwithpeople">Get in touch with people</h2>
<p>Been doing much better this month, with the aim of chatting with someone different every day.</p>
<h2 id="dontuseelectronicsthirtyminutesbeforeisleep">Don't use electronics thirty minutes before I sleep</h2>
<p>Not doing so well on this. I tried to start meditating before sleep, but I'm not too great at meditation it seems. My aim is start getting at least 15 minutes of meditation in every night.</p>
<h2 id="makemaps">Make maps</h2>
<p>No progress.</p>]]></description>
            <author>mail@lukehansford.me (Luke Hansford)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The State of My Resolutions, August 2015]]></title>
            <link>http://lukehansford.me/posts/resolutions-aug-2015/</link>
            <guid>http://lukehansford.me/posts/resolutions-aug-2015/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In order to keep tabs on the progress of my resolutions for 2015, I'm going to try
and do a writeup at the end of each month to see how I've gone.</p>
<h2 id="learnmalay">Learn Malay</h2>
<p>I started to study a bit more in July, but it has been more about catchup then learning anything new.</p>
<h2 id="getatattoo">Get a tattoo</h2>
<p>No progress.</p>
<h2 id="writeabook">Write a book</h2>
<p>No progress, but I've started to write a bit more in July, which will hopefully lead to something more substantial.</p>
<h2 id="makeabook">Make a book</h2>
<p>No progress.</p>
<h2 id="releaseanapp">Release an app</h2>
<p>Not much progress. I've been working on a wiki-style website for music resources and am contemplating a OS X app, but with no solid plan at the moment.</p>
<h2 id="makecandles">Make candles</h2>
<p>I no longer intend to complete this project.</p>
<h2 id="bedebtfree">Be debt free</h2>
<p>A little bit spent, a little paid, I'm probably back at where I was at the beginning of the month.</p>
<h2 id="goonalongdistancecyclingtrip">Go on a long-distance cycling trip</h2>
<p>No progress.</p>
<h2 id="startabandplayshowsreleasemusic">Start a band, play shows, release music</h2>
<p>I purchased some gear (Volca Sampler, DI) to try making some electronic music on my own. Nothing solid put down yet though.</p>
<h2 id="getintouchwithpeople">Get in touch with people</h2>
<p>Still not doing this as frequently as I'd like.</p>
<h2 id="dontuseelectronicsthirtyminutesbeforeisleep">Don't use electronics thirty minutes before I sleep</h2>
<p>Did pretty terribly at this in July (mostly because Evelyn is back in Malaysia).</p>
<h2 id="makemaps">Make maps</h2>
<p>Only worked on this a couple of times in July.</p>]]></description>
            <author>mail@lukehansford.me (Luke Hansford)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The State of My Resolutions, Feb 2015]]></title>
            <link>http://lukehansford.me/posts/resolutions-feb-2015/</link>
            <guid>http://lukehansford.me/posts/resolutions-feb-2015/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In order to keep tabs on the progress of my resolutions for 2015, I'm going to try
and do a writeup at the end of each month to see how I've gone.</p>
<h2 id="learnmalay">Learn Malay</h2>
<p>This resolution if going very well. I've managed to put in at least 30 minutes of
study for 4 out of 5 days in January, and my word count is at about 250.</p>
<h2 id="getatattoo">Get a tattoo</h2>
<p>Haven't got a tattoo yet - I'm still dwelling on what to get (and where).</p>
<h2 id="writeabook">Write a book</h2>
<p>No progress on this yet, though I have some concepts for a story floating around
in my head.</p>
<h2 id="makeabook">Make a book</h2>
<p>This is coming along pretty well. The content of the book I'm putting together,
is about 75% done.</p>
<h2 id="releaseanapp">Release an app</h2>
<p>I've been hemming and hawing over this one. Today I'm going to have another crack
at getting started.</p>
<h2 id="makecandles">Make candles</h2>
<p>No progress on this.</p>
<h2 id="bedebtfree">Be debt free</h2>
<p>Definitely no progress in this. I'm still awaiting my first pay day for my new job.</p>
<h2 id="goonalongdistancecyclingtrip">Go on a long-distance cycling trip</h2>
<p>Same as above, waiting for pay to purchase a bike.</p>
<h2 id="startabandplayshowsreleasemusic">Start a band, play shows, release music</h2>
<p>I've been playing guitar, but yet to start playing with other people.</p>
<h2 id="getintouchwithpeople">Get in touch with people</h2>
<p>Nope nope nope, failing hard on this one. I'm going to start thoroughly tracking
this in the hopes I've getting better at it.</p>
<h2 id="dontuseelectronicsthirtyminutesbeforeisleep">Don't use electronics thirty minutes before I sleep</h2>
<p>Not to great at this. Sometimes I do, but I would say it's only 25% of the time.</p>
<h2 id="makemaps">Make maps</h2>
<p>No progress on this.</p>]]></description>
            <author>mail@lukehansford.me (Luke Hansford)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The State of My Resolutions, July 2015]]></title>
            <link>http://lukehansford.me/posts/resolutions-jul-2015/</link>
            <guid>http://lukehansford.me/posts/resolutions-jul-2015/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In order to keep tabs on the progress of my resolutions for 2015, I'm going to try
and do a writeup at the end of each month to see how I've gone.</p>
<h2 id="learnmalay">Learn Malay</h2>
<p>I did almost no study in June. I'm going to have to make a concerted effort to get back on that horse.</p>
<h2 id="getatattoo">Get a tattoo</h2>
<p>No progress.</p>
<h2 id="writeabook">Write a book</h2>
<p>No progress.</p>
<h2 id="makeabook">Make a book</h2>
<p>I've finished the design work, but I've been delaying on researching printing options.</p>
<h2 id="releaseanapp">Release an app</h2>
<p>No progress. I'm currently working on a new website project called cassette.space.</p>
<h2 id="makecandles">Make candles</h2>
<p>I no longer intend to complete this project.</p>
<h2 id="bedebtfree">Be debt free</h2>
<p>Money has been tight this month, and probably will be next month as well. I've started to keep a proper budget so that I can keep track of how much I'm spending.</p>
<h2 id="goonalongdistancecyclingtrip">Go on a long-distance cycling trip</h2>
<p>No progress.</p>
<h2 id="startabandplayshowsreleasemusic">Start a band, play shows, release music</h2>
<p>No progress.</p>
<h2 id="getintouchwithpeople">Get in touch with people</h2>
<p>Still not doing this as frequently as I'd like.</p>
<h2 id="dontuseelectronicsthirtyminutesbeforeisleep">Don't use electronics thirty minutes before I sleep</h2>
<p>I've taken to reading more often before I sleep (on my Nexus 7 tablet though).</p>
<h2 id="makemaps">Make maps</h2>
<p>No progress.</p>]]></description>
            <author>mail@lukehansford.me (Luke Hansford)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The State of My Resolutions, June 2015]]></title>
            <link>http://lukehansford.me/posts/resolutions-jun-2015/</link>
            <guid>http://lukehansford.me/posts/resolutions-jun-2015/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In order to keep tabs on the progress of my resolutions for 2015, I'm going to try
and do a writeup at the end of each month to see how I've gone.</p>
<h2 id="learnmalay">Learn Malay</h2>
<p>I've really fallen behind on studying Malay. The key to getting back at it will be to start waking up at 6 agian and working on it.</p>
<h2 id="getatattoo">Get a tattoo</h2>
<p>No progress.</p>
<h2 id="writeabook">Write a book</h2>
<p>No progress.</p>
<h2 id="makeabook">Make a book</h2>
<p>I've done a bit of design work on this in the last week or so. Hopefully I can get it polished off by the end of this month.</p>
<h2 id="releaseanapp">Release an app</h2>
<p>No progress.</p>
<h2 id="makecandles">Make candles</h2>
<p>No progress.</p>
<h2 id="bedebtfree">Be debt free</h2>
<p>A little progress.</p>
<h2 id="goonalongdistancecyclingtrip">Go on a long-distance cycling trip</h2>
<p>No progress.</p>
<h2 id="startabandplayshowsreleasemusic">Start a band, play shows, release music</h2>
<p>No progress.</p>
<h2 id="getintouchwithpeople">Get in touch with people</h2>
<p>Still not doing this as frequently as I'd like</p>
<h2 id="dontuseelectronicsthirtyminutesbeforeisleep">Don't use electronics thirty minutes before I sleep</h2>
<p>Still failing.</p>
<h2 id="makemaps">Make maps</h2>
<p>I've been able to do a lot more of this in the last week. I've been collecting language data and am close to finishing off the Americas.</p>]]></description>
            <author>mail@lukehansford.me (Luke Hansford)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The State of My Resolutions, Mar 2015]]></title>
            <link>http://lukehansford.me/posts/resolutions-mar-2015/</link>
            <guid>http://lukehansford.me/posts/resolutions-mar-2015/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In order to keep tabs on the progress of my resolutions for 2015, I'm going to try
and do a writeup at the end of each month to see how I've gone.</p>
<h2 id="learnmalay">Learn Malay</h2>
<p>I dropped off a bit last month with my Malay study - I'd wager that I only studied around 50% of the days in February.</p>
<h2 id="getatattoo">Get a tattoo</h2>
<p>Still undecided on what to get for this.</p>
<h2 id="writeabook">Write a book</h2>
<p>No progress.</p>
<h2 id="makeabook">Make a book</h2>
<p>No progress.</p>
<h2 id="releaseanapp">Release an app</h2>
<p>I've worked a little bit on a todo.txt app, but I'm not sure if I still want to follow through on it.</p>
<h2 id="makecandles">Make candles</h2>
<p>No progress.</p>
<h2 id="bedebtfree">Be debt free</h2>
<p>Negative progress, but I have the intention of paying off some in the next week.</p>
<h2 id="goonalongdistancecyclingtrip">Go on a long-distance cycling trip</h2>
<p>No progress.</p>
<h2 id="startabandplayshowsreleasemusic">Start a band, play shows, release music</h2>
<p>No progress.</p>
<h2 id="getintouchwithpeople">Get in touch with people</h2>
<p>No progress.</p>
<h2 id="dontuseelectronicsthirtyminutesbeforeisleep">Don't use electronics thirty minutes before I sleep</h2>
<p>No progress.</p>
<h2 id="makemaps">Make maps</h2>
<p>No progress.</p>]]></description>
            <author>mail@lukehansford.me (Luke Hansford)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The State of My Resolutions, May 2015]]></title>
            <link>http://lukehansford.me/posts/resolutions-may-2015/</link>
            <guid>http://lukehansford.me/posts/resolutions-may-2015/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In order to keep tabs on the progress of my resolutions for 2015, I'm going to try
and do a writeup at the end of each month to see how I've gone.</p>
<h2 id="learnmalay">Learn Malay</h2>
<p>I had dengue fever in April, so I fell of the wagon with my Malay study. The last few days though I've been getting a reasonable amount of time in.</p>
<h2 id="getatattoo">Get a tattoo</h2>
<p>No progress.</p>
<h2 id="writeabook">Write a book</h2>
<p>No progress.</p>
<h2 id="makeabook">Make a book</h2>
<p>No progress.</p>
<h2 id="releaseanapp">Release an app</h2>
<p>No progress.</p>
<h2 id="makecandles">Make candles</h2>
<p>No progress.</p>
<h2 id="bedebtfree">Be debt free</h2>
<p>Slightly negative progress.</p>
<h2 id="goonalongdistancecyclingtrip">Go on a long-distance cycling trip</h2>
<p>No progress.</p>
<h2 id="startabandplayshowsreleasemusic">Start a band, play shows, release music</h2>
<p>No progress.</p>
<h2 id="getintouchwithpeople">Get in touch with people</h2>
<p>Didn't really do well at this in April.</p>
<h2 id="dontuseelectronicsthirtyminutesbeforeisleep">Don't use electronics thirty minutes before I sleep</h2>
<p>Pretty much failed at this.</p>
<h2 id="makemaps">Make maps</h2>
<p>No progress.</p>]]></description>
            <author>mail@lukehansford.me (Luke Hansford)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The State of My Resolutions, November 2015]]></title>
            <link>http://lukehansford.me/posts/resolutions-nov-2015/</link>
            <guid>http://lukehansford.me/posts/resolutions-nov-2015/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>So at this point in time my new year resolutions have kind of fallen by the wayside. Some of them
are unlikely to happen by the end of the year, while others I've lost interest in. I'm not going to
hold my self to the latter as there's no point doing something I'd rather not do. The tattoo thing
I'm on the fence about (mainly I don't know what I would get), the candles thing is over (Ikea candles work
 just fine), and I've been too preoccupied to work on maps or do much writing.</p>
<p>Two things I have been doing in the last month is working on a new Frequency Asia project, which I
guess could be considered an app, and getting in contact with people a lot more often. I've also
started playing around with <a href="http://www.fastcompany.com/3053036/how-to-be-a-success-at-everything/the-simple-technique-to-fit-a-40-hour-work-week-into-167-h">this method</a> to better manage my time. I like how it's going so far.</p>]]></description>
            <author>mail@lukehansford.me (Luke Hansford)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The State of My Resolutions, September 2015]]></title>
            <link>http://lukehansford.me/posts/resolutions-sep-2015/</link>
            <guid>http://lukehansford.me/posts/resolutions-sep-2015/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2015 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In order to keep tabs on the progress of my resolutions for 2015, I'm going to try
and do a writeup at the end of each month to see how I've gone.</p>
<h2 id="learnmalay">Learn Malay</h2>
<p>I haven't really studied much Malay in the last month. I need to get in the swing of doing it when I wake up.</p>
<h2 id="getatattoo">Get a tattoo</h2>
<p>No progress.</p>
<h2 id="writeabook">Write a book</h2>
<p>I'm doing a bit of writing about the Atom editor, with the idea of compiling the articles into an E-book once I have written enough.</p>
<h2 id="makeabook">Make a book</h2>
<p>No progress.</p>
<h2 id="releaseanapp">Release an app</h2>
<p>Back to square one again. I'm stuck in the cycle of trying to identify a killer app, or at the very least something I'd want to use.</p>
<h2 id="makecandles">Make candles</h2>
<p>I no longer intend to complete this project.</p>
<h2 id="bedebtfree">Be debt free</h2>
<p>A wee bit of progress on this one.</p>
<h2 id="goonalongdistancecyclingtrip">Go on a long-distance cycling trip</h2>
<p>No progress.</p>
<h2 id="startabandplayshowsreleasemusic">Start a band, play shows, release music</h2>
<p>Good progress on this one. I've released two tracks under the Dallol moniker this month. I'm far from being able to perform live, but I'm getting there hopefully.</p>
<h2 id="getintouchwithpeople">Get in touch with people</h2>
<p>Doing a bit better on this this month, though I'm starting to realise that half the problem is that my friends are too much like me in this regards.</p>
<h2 id="dontuseelectronicsthirtyminutesbeforeisleep">Don't use electronics thirty minutes before I sleep</h2>
<p>A mixed month in relation to this goal. I haven't been sleeping well as of late, so maybe I need to double down on this.</p>
<h2 id="makemaps">Make maps</h2>
<p>No progress.</p>]]></description>
            <author>mail@lukehansford.me (Luke Hansford)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Idle-Until-Urgent Pattern in React]]></title>
            <link>http://lukehansford.me/posts/the-idle-until-urgent-pattern-in-react/</link>
            <guid>http://lukehansford.me/posts/the-idle-until-urgent-pattern-in-react/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 14:10:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>One thing I've been struggling with recently working on <a href="https://fishbrain.com">fishbrain.com</a> is
the high cost of hydrating server rendered React. While server-side rendering brings us a lot of
benefits, it does take a fair amount of time to hyrdate, which can be particularly frustrating if
you're hydrating elements of the page that the user is not immediately going to interact with, or
even possibly see.</p>
<p>One potential work around is to use the Idle-Until-Urgent pattern. Philip Walton does a far better
job than I can explaining the details of the pattern in <a href="https://philipwalton.com/articles/idle-until-urgent/">his blog post on the matter</a>, so
I'd recommend checking that out, but the basic gist of the pattern is:</p>
<ul>
<li>to delay the execution of code until the browser not executing any code (this is the 'idle').</li>
<li>allow some sort of trigger to execute the code before the idle stage if needed (this is the 'urgent').</li>
</ul>
<p>What this means for our React use case, is that we would delay hydration of a component either until
the browser stops executing code, or, if the user interacts with the unhydrated element, we can
hydrate it on demand. My implementation was initially based on <a href="https://dev.to/uzumakinarut0/optimizing-react-performance-part-i-n83">another great article from Kumar
Swapnil</a>.</p>
<h2 id="thecode">The code</h2>
<p>This a component that will wrap around another React component to make it use the idle-until-urgent
pattern:</p>
<pre><code class="javascript language-javascript">import React, { useState, ReactNode, useEffect } from 'react';
// This is a simple library we use to tell us if the code is running in Node or in a browser.
import isNode from 'detect-node';

export const IdleUntilUrgent = ({ children, htmlElement }) =&gt; {
  const [callbackId, setCallbackId] = useState(null);
  const [renderChild, setRenderChild] = useState(false);

  useEffect(() =&gt; {
    if (!isNode) {
      if (typeof window.requestIdleCallback !== 'undefined') {
        // https://caniuse.com/#search=requestIdleCallback
        setCallbackId(
          window.requestIdleCallback(() =&gt; {
            setRenderChild(true);
          }),
        );
      } else {
        setTimeout(() =&gt; {
          setRenderChild(true);
        });
      }
    }
  }, []);

  if (!isNode &amp;&amp; !renderChild) {
    // eslint-disable-next-line react/no-danger-with-children
    return React.createElement(
      htmlElement,
      {
        dangerouslySetInnerHTML: { __html: '' },
        suppressHydrationWarning: true,
        onClick: () =&gt; setRenderChild(true),
      },
      null,
    );
  }

  // Cancel the already scheduled render, if any
  if (!isNode &amp;&amp; callbackId) {
    window.cancelIdleCallback(callbackId);
  }

  return children;
};
</code></pre>
<p>In use it would look something like this:</p>
<pre><code class="jsx language-jsx">&lt;IdleUntilUrgent htmlElement="button"&gt;
  &lt;button&gt;Click me&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;/IdleUntilUrgent&gt;
</code></pre>
<h2 id="breakingitdown">Breaking it down</h2>
<p>First we store the two bits of state we need. A callback ID (so we can cancel the callback if needed),
and a flag telling us if the child should be rendered or not.</p>
<pre><code class="javascript language-javascript">const [callbackId, setCallbackId] = useState(null);
const [renderChild, setRenderChild] = useState(false);
</code></pre>
<p>Next we use a <code>useEffect</code> hook, triggered only once, that will set a callback using the <code>requestIdleCallback</code>
API. This will trigger whenever the browser is idle. As it is not supported in all browsers, we
have a backup option of using a timeout, which will trigger on the next event loop.</p>
<pre><code class="javascript language-javascript">useEffect(() =&gt; {
  if (!isNode) {
    if (typeof window.requestIdleCallback !== 'undefined') {
      // https://caniuse.com/#search=requestIdleCallback
      setCallbackId(
        window.requestIdleCallback(() =&gt; {
          setRenderChild(true);
        }),
      );
    } else {
      setTimeout(() =&gt; {
        setRenderChild(true);
      });
    }
  }
}, []);
</code></pre>
<p>If we're rendering in the browser, and we're still waiting for our idle or urgent callback, we want
to skip hydration. This is possible by returning a react element with <code>dangerouslySetInnerHTML={{ __html: '' }}</code>.
One thing to note is <code>onClick: () =&gt; setRenderChild(true)</code>. This is our "Urgent" part of the pattern - if a user
clicks the element we want to hydrate the component immediately.
Another important thing to note is that this will only work if we're rendering the same type of HTML
element - a pitfall I ran into by intially writing something like: <code>&lt;div dangerouslySetInnerHTML={{ __html: '' }}&gt;&lt;button&gt;click me&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</code>.</p>
<pre><code class="javascript language-javascript">if (!isNode &amp;&amp; !renderChild) {
  // eslint-disable-next-line react/no-danger-with-children
  return React.createElement(
    htmlElement,
    {
      dangerouslySetInnerHTML: { __html: '' },
      suppressHydrationWarning: true,
      onClick: () =&gt; setRenderChild(true),
    },
    null,
  );
}
</code></pre>
<p>The last part is pretty straightforward. Either we're in Node, and we want to render as normal, or
<code>renderChild</code> is true, meaning that idle callback was triggered or the user clicked on the element,
so it's time to hydrate (cleaning up our callback along the way).</p>
<pre><code class="javascript language-javascript">if (!isNode &amp;&amp; callbackId) {
  window.cancelIdleCallback(callbackId);
}

return children;
</code></pre>
<h2 id="performanceimpact">Performance Impact</h2>
<p>We opted to test this out on one of our most heavily visited pages on fishbrain.com - the waters
pages (<a href="https://fishbrain.com/fishing-waters/Icur1OcV/brisbane-river">here's an example of one such page</a>). This
is what the flamegraph for the React render looked like:</p>
<p><img src="initial.png" alt="Flamegraph if initial render" /></p>
<p>Some of the components run so deep that they wouldn't fit on the screen. A particularly bad offender
was the Tabs component:</p>
<p><img src="tabs.png" alt="Flamegraph of Tabs" /></p>
<p>From this we we're able to identify 4 particular components that were taking a long time to
hydrate while not being something that need render immediately for any user benefit. Wrapping
these components led to a decreased from approximately 450ms to hydrate to &lt;100ms!</p>
<p><img src="with-idle-until-urgent.png" alt="Flamegraph after adding IdleUntilUrgent" /></p>
<p>We also found that the IdleUntilUrgent components would hydrate pretty quickly after the initial
hydration (usually less than 0.5s), so only an extremely quick user would be able to interact with
an idled component.</p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>All of the above being said, this is not a pattern we're going to be using this all over the place.
As is usual with these kind of performance hacks, it's something we only want to use in particular
cases, but for those cases it's an impressively useful tool.</p>]]></description>
            <author>mail@lukehansford.me (Luke Hansford)</author>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>